Welcome to the eLearning
session Error Handling
欢迎来到 elearning 课程,
in Ensemble HL7 Productions.
Ensemble HL7 Productions 的错误处理。
No matter how well designed your
production is, problems occur.
无论你设计的 production 如何的好，总会有问题发生。
For example, messages
come into Ensemble
比如，在进入到 Ensemble 的消息中，
that are not in
the right format,
有些格式部队，///////////////////////////////////////////////???
inbound or outbound
connections go down,
或者入口或出口的连接断了，
or other problems occur
that we can not foresee.
或者有我们无法预知的错误发生。
Ensemble provides
many different options
Ensemble 提供了许多可以
that help us to handle
these problems and errors.
帮我们进行问题和错误处理的选项。
The first thing we want
to do is set up alerting,
我们首先要做的是设置警报，
so that we know
when problems occur
因为我们能知有问题发生，
and, therefore, can
fix them quickly.
从而能快速解决问题。
You can choose to be alerted
in many different ways,
你有很多种发法作报警，
including receiving an
email or text message,
包括 email 或者短信，
or it can just write the
error message to a log file.
或者可以将错误消息记录到日志中。
Let's take a look at
our Demo Production
让我们来看一下我们的 Demo Production.
Looking at our
configuration page,
在配置页面中，我们可
notice each component has a
setting called Alert On Error.
注意到，每个组件都有一个 "Alert On Error" 的设置。
Our To_Billing
Business Operation
我们的 To_Billing Business Operation
has the setting checked.
这个设置有选中。
When a component
triggers an alert,
当一个组件触发一个警报时，
it sends a message to
Ens.Alert, a Message Router
它会发送消息到 Ens.Alert, 这是一个
that handles these alerts.
处理警报的消息路由。
This component is
automatically added
这个组建在你创建 HL7 Production//////////////////////////////????
when you create
an HL7 production
的时候自动加入，
and it must be
called this to work.
而且必须能正常工作。
Ens.Alert, because it
is a Message Router,
Ens.Alert 因为也是一个消息路由，
can route our message just
like any other Message Router,
可以象其它消息路由那样根据
based on conditions
such as time of day,
条件，比如每天的某个时间，
component that caused the error,
or any other condition that you
造成错误的组建，以及其它你设置的
set up.
条件，路由我们的消息。
Let's look at our Business
Rules in Ens.Alert.
让我们看一下我们 Business 规则中的 Ens.Alert.
In our example, we will
send this alert message
在我们的例子中，我们会发 email
to our email alert
Business Operation that
到我们的 email 报警 Business Operation,
will send out an email
based on the component that
其会根据组建触发的警报
triggered the alert.
发送 email.
However, alerting
can send its messages
然而，警报也可以发送消息
to any Business Process
or Business Operation
到任何 Business Process 或者 Business Operation，
and, therefore, is not
limited to only emails.
因此，这不局限于 email.
Right now, I've set
up this Production so
现在，我们就来进行设置，
that my To_Billing
File Business Operation
这样我的 To_Billing 文件 Business Operation
is trying to write to
an invalid file path.
写到无效的文件路径时，会报警。
Let's put a message in
and see what happens.
让我们发一个消息，然后看会发生什么。
Based on how I've configured
my Production, when
基于我的 Production 的配置，
I send a message
through, Ensemble
当我发送一条消息时，Ensemble
will put an alert
in my event log,
会放一条警报到事件日志中，
as well as send me
an email letting
这和发送一个邮件让我
me know that the file path
of the Business Operation
知道 Buinsess Operation 的路径////////////////////////////////????
is set to a bad location.
有错是一个道理。
Let's take a look at our event
log and see the alert message.
让我们来看一下我们的事件日志，可看到警报消息。
You'll notice the top
entry is an alert message,
你会注意到在头部，有个警报消息，
saying that it
cannot open the file.
消息内容为 "不能打开文件"。
And the second one
is an error message,
而第二条是个错误消息，
also saying that it
cannot open the file.
也是说 “不能打开文件"。
We can then view,
in our Visual Trace,
然后我们可以看我们的 Visual Trace,
how the messages are
passed through Ensemble.
看消息是如何在 Ensemble 中传递的。
Notice there is an alert request
from To_Billing to my Ens.Alert
注意到这个警报消息来自于 To_Billing
component.
然后到达 Ens.Alert 组件的。
Ens.Alert then sends a
message to EMailAlert,
Ens.Alert 然后发送消息到 EMailAlert,
which will then
send out my email,
如果我已经配置了我的email 地址
if I have configured
my email address.
其会发送 email 我。
Sometimes, another
error that can occur
有的时候，错误发生在/////////////////////////////////????
is the sending system
sends a message.
发送消息的系统发送了
in, in the wrong format.
格式错误的消息。
Perhaps we were
expecting 2.3.1 ADT_A01
也许我们要的是 2.3.1 ADT_A01
but actually receive a custom
schema, ADT_A01 instead.
但是我们收到的是用户自定义 schema 的 ADT_A01。
In order to trap this
message as a bad message,
为了捕获错误消息，
we need to take a look at our
message router's validation
我们需要看一下我们的消息路由的
setting.
验证设置。
This setting, if on, based
on the possible flags
如果这个设置是开的，
that you can view when
clicking on that setting name,
你可以点击设置的名称
checks the message against
the Business Service's Message
察看来自于 Business Service 消息的
Schema Category.
Schema 类型。
If it does not match the
schema, it fails validation
如果 schema 不匹配，那么不能通过验证，
and is then sent to
the component noted
并且会发送到称之为
in the BadMessageHandler
setting.
BadMessageHandler 的组件处。
By default, when you
create an HL7 Production,
缺省情况下，当你创建一个 HL7 Production,
Ensemble automatically
creates a component
Ensemble 会自动产生一个
called BadMessageHandler.
BadMessageHandler 的组件。
We can type this name in our
BadMessageHandler setting.
我们可以在我们的 BadMessageHandler 设置中输入这个名字。
If we would also like to
raise an alert if there
如果我们还要产生一个警报，
is a bad message, we can
set the Alert On Bad Message
如果这是一个坏消息，我们可以设置
"Alert On Bad Message"
setting to true.
为真。
Often, a receiving system
will send the message back
常常，在接受方会发送回复
to acknowledge a
message was sent.
已表明消息发出。
If the message back
acknowledges the message
如果回复的消息表明消息收到，
but recognizes that there was
a problem with the message,
但是消息有问题存在，
we need to handle this error.
我们需要对此错误进行处理。
Reply Code Actions is a setting
on the Business Operation
"Reply Code Actions" 是 Business Operation 处的一个设置
that lets you specify
responses, based
其允许你，根据不同的
on receipt of several different
acknowledgement or ACK codes.
确认方式或者 ACK 代码，指定回复。
For example, if I'm
receipt of a NACK,
比如，如果我接受到一个 NACK,
I would like to disable
the Business Operation.
我会停用这个 Business Operation.
I could put in this
text box, :?E=D,
我在 "Reply Code Action" 中，
like you see here in
Reply Code Actions.
输入 ":?E=D", 如同你看到的那样。
This setting means
that, on an error,
这个设置表示，当有错误发生时候，
we're going to disable our
Business Operation, the
我们会停用我们的 Business Operation,
to To_Lab component.
即 To_Lab 组件。
Now, let's send the message
through and see how this works.
现在，我们发送一个消息，看是否能起作用。
Notice that we can see that
the Business Operation has
注意到，这个 Business Operation
been disabled when it
receives the NACK back.
当其收到 NACK 回复时即停用。
Up until now, To_Billing
has had a bad file path,
到目前为止，To_Billing 有一个错误文件路径，
but I've just corrected this
and now it has an OK file path.
但是，我已经更正，现在其的路径是正确的。
All the messages that were sent
to T0_Billing while this file
当文件路径是错误的时候，所有发送到 To_Billing 的
path was incorrect
were automatically
消息，会被自动地
sent to that text file.
发送到这个文本文件。
We didn't have to
do anything else.
我们没有为此作任何其它的事情。
However, any messages
that were built up To_Lab
但是，所有被发送do To_Lab 的消息///////////////////////////???
are still waiting on the queue.
会等候在队列中。
Let's talk next about
how to resend messages
现在我们来谈谈如何重发
that might be sitting
on the To_Lab queue
在 To_Lab 队列中的消息
and send them now to To_Billing.
到 To_Billing。
When problems occur
with messages,
当消息有问题发生时，
often you may need to
resend the messages.
我们常需要重新发送消息。
We can do this directly
inside of Ensemble.
我们可以直接在 Ensemble 内来实现。
To resend, we're going to
go to the Message Viewer.
为了重发，我们点击 "Message Viewer".
Here, we can select a message.
在这里，我们选中一条消息。
In this case, I want to
select my message that's
对于这个例子，我要选一条
queued up on To_Lab.
在 To_Lab 队列中的消息。
I can then click Resend.
然后我可以点击 "Resend”。
Notice we can also
choose a new destination
注意到，我们也可选新的目的地，
and even edit the
message before resending.
甚至在重发前可以编辑这消息。
Let's edit a message and
resend to another component.
让我们编辑者消息，然后重发到另一个组件。
I can change values in
this document and then,
我可以修改在这文档中的值，然后
at the bottom of the
page, I can click Resend.
在这页的底部，点击 "Resend"。
Notice here that a copy of our
message was sent to To_Billing.
注意到，这里有我们消息的复制发送到 To_Billing.
Let's next discuss how to
work with suspended messages.
接下去，我们讨论一下怎么处理挂起的消息。
Some Business Operations are
designed to suspend messages
有些 Business 被设计成当有
when a message fails, or
operators can manually
消息发送失败时，消息被挂起，或者是操作员
suspend messages with the
intention of re-submitting them
可以手工挂起消息，然后重发这些消息。////////////////////////////////????
later.
These suspended messages
are put in a special queue
这些挂起的消息可以放在一个特殊的队列上，
that we can view and use
to manage these messages.
从那里，我们可以察看和管理这些消息。
Let's first suspend
the message manually.
我们首先来手工挂起一个消息。
My Business Operation is
currently in a retry state,
我的 Business Operation 目前处于重试状态，
because my file path is set
to an incorrect file path
因为我的文件路径不正确
and I've set failure timeout to
-1, to keep retrying forever.
并且我设置 "failure timeout" 为 -1, 这样会一直重试。
Setting failure timeout
to -1 is usually
设置 "failure timeout" 为 -1
what you'd like
the setting to be.
通常就是为了这个目的。
So now, if I go to the
Jobs tab on the right,
现在，如果我们到右手边的 "Jobs" 标签页，
I have the option to
suspend this message.
我可以看到挂起消息的选项。
Let's suspend it and
see where it goes.
让我们挂起这消息，然后看发生什么。
Now if I go back to
my Management Portal,
现在，如果回到管理门户，
I can view my suspended messages
by going to Ensemble, View
我可以到 Ensmeble,View，suspended Messages 菜单
and then Suspended Messages.
察看我挂起的消息
Notice here I have two
messages that are suspended,
这里注意到，我有两条挂起的消息，
and I have the option
here to Resubmit
并且有个选项 "Resubmit”，
my message, Edit and
Resubmit, Discard, or Delete.
重发消息，以及 "Edit","Discard","Delete" 其它选项。
Delete will officially
delete that message
"delete" 会真正从数据库中删除这条消息，
from your database, Discard
will leave that message
而 "Discard" 会保留这消息，
to be viewed in
the Message Viewer
只是在 "Message Viewer" 中查看消息时，
but will put it in
a discarded state,
会看到有个 "discarded" 的状态。
Resubmit just does
a simple resubmit
"resubmit" 只是简单的提交
and sending that
message on again,
并且重发，
and then we can also
edit before resubmitting.
我们在重发前，也可以编辑消息。
I'm going to choose to
simply resubmit this message.
我现在只是简单地重发这消息。
Thank you for watching
this eLearning session.
感谢您收看这 eLearning 课程。
Hopefully, you've
learned a little bit more
希望您能从中学习到一些
about error handling
in Ensemble.
Ensmeble 错误处理。